tntech.edu 2010-06-12

# Privacy Policy | Tennessee Tech University

Tennessee Tech University understands the importance of protecting the privacy of personal information, especially in today’s electronic environment. This privacy policy covers the Web Pages belonging to Tennessee Tech University, located in Cookeville, Tennessee in the United States. This statement applies to all University offices that interact with University data.

### What the Tennessee Tech Privacy Policy Means

  * We inform you how we use any personally identifiable information that we gather on our Web Pages
  * We maintain security and safeguards for any information that we gather on our Web Pages
  * You have control over the information you decide to submit to us
  * You can opt out of receiving information from us 

### Information Collected Automatically

When you browse our Web Pages, certain statistics are automatically collected for marketing and research. This information is housed outside of the University on Google’s web servers. This information could include, not is not limited to:

  * IP address
  * Referring site
  * Date, time, and duration of activity
  * Operating system
  * Screen resolution
  * Browser type
  * Hostname
  * Connection speed
  * Web pages visited
  * Network location 
  * Passwords and accounts accessed 
    * No University official will ever ask for your password via an e-mail or off of the tntech.edu/ttualumni.org domains.
  * Volume of data storage and transfers
  * Server space used for e-mail

### Detailed Session Logging

In cases of suspected violations of Tennessee Tech policies especially unauthorized access to computing systems, the system administrator concerned may authorize detailed session logging. This may involve capturing and retaining a complete keystroke log of an entire session. In addition, a system administrator for the equipment involved may authorize limited searching of user files on individual or networked computers to gather evidence on a suspected violation.

Such Policies are as follows:

  * Web Publishing Policy
  * TTU Code of Computing Practice
  * TBR Information Technology Policy
  * Guidelines for Acceptable Use of E-Mail for Mass Mailing
  * ITC Policy on Recreational Computing
  * TECnet Acceptable Use Policy
  * TTU Computer Software Policy
  * TTU Virus Protection Policy
  * Computing Resource Security Policy
  * Data Security Policy
  * ResNet Policy

### Alternative to Web site Transactions

Tennessee Tech web sites provide information and services for students, faculty, staff, alumni, and members of the general public. If you prefer not to provide any information to the University via the web site, you may contact the unit responsible for the service to learn about options available to you for conducting the business in person, by mail, or by telephone.

### Use and Sharing Restrictions

Tennessee Tech does not sell, distribute, or use for anything other than official University business any confidential information it collects online. University, Tennessee Board of Regents, and Federal Law protect the confidentiality of student educational records and employee personnel information.

  * The University will use data only for University-related business, outreach, service, and development programs.
  * Data will be shared only with University staff that directly need access to the information for University purposes, with authorized users for directory information, and with approved partners working with the University as contractors. 
  * The University will not share personal information with third parties for their use independent of authorized University programs.
  * The University may disclose your personal information as required by law in connection with judicial or administrative proceedings or if the information is necessary to protect the institution.
  * The University may disclose your personal information if the information is necessary to protect the health or safety of any person. 

### External Links

External links are provided as a courtesy online. The University, in most cases, does not endorse or sponsor these third parties. Any information collected by these third parties is by your discretion, as the University does not have control over third party information.

### Security

Although every effort is made to secure network communications and traffic, the University cannot ensure the privacy of all online communications. Individuals using online services should take the necessary and appropriate steps to protect personal information, such as closing web browsers when finished in labs and public areas. Failure to do so may result in personal information being viewed by others using the same computer at a later time.

The University accepts credit cards online for a variety of goods and services, including merchandise and tuition. Eagle Online, University Advancement, and Tennessee Tech University Marketplace are the only areas that currently accept credit card transactions. All University credit card transactions are encrypted. Confidential information entered to complete a transaction will not be used for any other purpose unless otherwise stated.

### Opt-Out Controls

The University has multiple means of communication with students, faculty, staff, alumni, and friends. Certain communications are internal and cannot be opted out of, especially those concerning campus health and safety. All other communications from University units provide opt-out controls within each communication.

Opt-out preferences are processed immediately and will be effective no later than 90 days after submission and has no duration of time.

### FERPA Rights to Privacy

The Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) (20 U.S.C. § 1232g; 34 CFR Part 99) is a Federal law that protects the privacy of student education records. The law applies to all schools that receive funds under an applicable program of the U.S. Department of Education.

FERPA gives parents certain rights with respect to their children's education records. These rights transfer to the student when he or she reaches the age of 18 or attends a school beyond the high school level. Students to whom the rights have transferred are "eligible students."

The law grants four specific rights to students:

  * the right to see the information that an institution has concerning a student
  * the right to seek an amendment to those records and, in certain cases, to append a statement to the record
  * the right to consent for disclosure of those records
  * the right to file a complaint with the Department of Education Compliance Office in Washington, D.C.

For more information on FERPA, please see the [Department of Education web site](http://www.ed.gov/policy/gen/guid/fpco/ferpa/index.html).

### Privacy Policy Changes and Maintenance

The University Privacy Policy is maintained by the Web and Digital Media Director in the Office of Public Affairs. The University has the right to change this policy at any time. All official changes will be posted via the web site. This statement is effective as of January 1, 2008.
